I was born on a small farm in
the northern region of Wall Rose.
It was on land owned by
the noble family of Reiss.
As far back as I can remember,
I was helping around the farm.
But, my mother was always reading books
and not once did I see her doing housework.
She was a beautiful woman...
At night, someone would
come for her in a wagon...
...and she'd go off to
the city wearing fancy clothes.
For me, that was just life as I knew it.
After I learned to read and write,
I picked up a book to imitate my mother.
Only then did I know how alone I was.
In all the books, parents cared
about their children.
They talked, hugged, fought...
or so the stories went.
I had never experienced any of those things.
One day, out of curiosity,
I decided to try hugging my mother.
I just wanted to see what
kind of face she would make.
Mother!
She ended up shoving me away, but that was
the first thing my mother ever did to me.
That's why it made me so happy.
If only I had the courage... to kill the girl...
Those were... the first words
my mother said to me.
After that, she left the house
and began living somewhere else.
And then, five years ago...
One night just days after Wall Maria fell...
For the very first time, I met my father.
Nice to meet you, Historia.
My name is Rod Reiss... I'm your father.
That man... He was the lord
ruling the land we lived on.
My mother I hadn't seen in years
looked terribly frightened.
Historia... You'll be living with me now.
This is a problem, Lord Reiss.
Let's avoid acting rashly now.
Did the fall of Wall Maria
make you a little scared?
Mother!
No! I am not the mother of that girl!
She has nothing to do with me!
Oh? Is that true, Lord Reiss?
Do you really have nothing to do
with this woman or child?
So be it...
These two here have nothing to do with me.
I thought that might be the case.
What?! What are you...?
You never existed.
You never worked at the estate either.
Nobody knows who you are.
That's not... Master!
Please tell them that's not true!
Mother...
If only...
If only I never had you!
Those were my mother's last words.
Wait.
Moments before I was to be killed,
my father proposed an idea.
That if I were to be sent far away and live out
a quiet life, perhaps they could spare me.
Your name will be Christa Lenz.
Please forgive me for everything.
In order to protect you, I had no other choice.
F-Father...
I was always thinking about you.
I've always dreamed of the day
I could hold you like this.
You're special... Royal blood runs through you.
It... does?
That's right, Historia.
Our Reiss family is the true royal line.
And because you're special, you're the one
and only person who can save all of humanity.
Now, let us go, Historia.
To the place it all began...
Sannes!
Are you... all right?!
Hey, don't tell me...
You didn't tell them anything, right?
Our loyalty to the King is more--
Sannes!
I can't stand to hear your voice anymore!
You've betrayed me since the very beginning!
To think how I trusted you!
Sannes! He never told us anything.
In fact, we never questioned him.
We threatened Ralph with a knife and
forced him to read this script that I wrote.
That's all.
Then...
I...
I betrayed the King?
Y-You devils!
I'm not trying to deny it, but... I'm sure
Nick thought the same thing about you.
That's why I said what I did.
That I was beginning to feel sorry for you.
Look at how pathetic you are!
Grown-ass men wailing and crying!
It serves you right, morons!
See how you like spending the rest
of your life shitting in a tiny cell!
See you.
Next in line...
This role of ours... There's an order to it.
When one's role is done,
another steps in to start the act again.
And thus, the world can never be rid of it.
Good luck, Hange.
Section Commander?
Sorry... I made a mess.
There was a cockroach.
I see... Just one kick of yours
should've blasted it to bits.
It's about time you fill them in.
Oh... Yeah, I should.
Eren will be eaten?!
Yeah.
Eren remembered a conversation
that went like this...
Do you resent me for it?
I'm not sure...
I... don't know.
You probably didn't want
to eat a human either...
Speculating based on that, Ymir was a
Titan wandering alone outside the wall.
Bertholdt, Reiner, and Annie
had a comrade that she ate.
When a Titan eats someone,
they don't change back into a human.
But what if a Titan ate
one of Reiner's comrades?
They're humans who can transform into Titans.
In other words, if a Titan eats someone with
that power, they revert back into a human.
Furthermore, they obtain
the power of those they eat.
In the other day's battle, Reiner was
throwing Titans at Eren, who had escaped.
Eren has the power to
control Titans with his scream.
He was trying to snatch
that power with those Titans.
In that case, Eren is just a vessel
who is bound to be replaced.
Basically, if the government has a Titan
of their own, they'll be the one to eat Eren.
Calm down.
Even if you go on a rampage,
they're not going to give Eren back to us.
Anyways, we head for
the lands of this Rod Reiss.
Get ready to leave at once.
Yes, sir!
I'll go tell Erwin what we learned
about the Reiss family.
I'm sure he's waiting to hear from us.
Right.
We can meet up on Reiss' land.
Hear from me at the usual spot.
Excuse me. Commander Erwin,
Pyxis is here for you.
The commander?
Yes, he wants to see you.
Let him in.
Sir!
Sorry about the late visit.
I just couldn't stand still, you see.
I finished reading your letter.
I came with some thoughts of my own.
But first I need to ask... Are you serious?
Yes.
In order to retake Wall Maria,
we'll overthrow the government.
I knew this would happen one day.
This cramped world can only hold people
for so long before they begin to lash out.
And when that time came, I'd have to
point my gun at the King as well.
If my guess proves correct, this plan will not
require military forces to take action.
Nor should it be necessary for anyone to die.
Oh? Do tell me then.
Is such a method possible?
However, the groundwork for this
to happen is not quite ready.
And if everything is not in order, me and
everyone else will be hanged, no doubt.
Oh, that's all?
In other words, it's another huge gamble.
It seems I may be a betting man.
The news should come shortly.
Until it arrives, I'd like you to hear
a story regarding my childhood.
Hmm?
My father... He was a teacher.
"An Intelligent Titan is conceived when a Pure Titan
lacking intelligence consumes some other Intelligent
Titan. By consuming an Intelligent Titan, it gains
consciousness as well as the consumed Titan's powers."
What in the world?
Section Commander, that was--
Yeah, I know.
Excuse me!
Erwin...
I thought as much.
My gamble was right after all, Commander.
One of the First Interior Squad confessed.
The current royal family is a fraud.
Reiss is the true royal family.
My word!
Right now, Squad Levi is underway
rescuing Eren and Historia.
Once they're recovered, we'll have
Historia Reiss enthroned as Queen.
As one possessing the true royal blood.
And you'll force the makeshift
King to relinquish the crown?
To the true Queen...
Without spilling any blood,
we will overthrow the government.
And in front of the people, we'll reveal that
the system as they know it has all been a lie.
Very well. I'll back your plan.
However, whether or not it should be
carried out is not for us to decide.
You understand that, don't you, Erwin?
Of course, Commander.
Did anything come of the Reiss investigation?
I found out as much as I could.
From all that I learned,
one curious incident stuck out.
Incident?
Commander Erwin! The Interior Squad
demands you turn yourself in!
They're making a scene in the middle of
the city that you organized a murder!
It seems the enemy's been
making plans of their own.
Hange, get far from here.
Huh?! What are you planning to do?
I need to be the face of the Scout Regiment.
You should act at your own discretion.
Furthermore, the next commander
of the Scout Regiment...
Hange Zoë, it's you.
The Scouts are in your hands.
Hey, he's here.
It's Erwin.
I take it you know who this is, Erwin?
The boss of Reeves Company.
Mr. Dimo Reeves.
Yesterday, and in this very place, Eren Jaeger
was abducted by underlings of Reeves.
However... that was all a mere scheme
between the Scouts and Reeves Company
in order to evade handing over
Eren Jaeger to the government.
And then... when Reeves was no longer needed,
they killed the man to keep him from talking.
The murderer is still at large
and must be holed up with Eren.
What a convenient story that is.
What you scoundrels are doing... It's the same
as monopolizing Eren's power for yourself.
And that act violates Clause Six
of the Charter of Humanity.
You know which that one is, don't you?
To prioritize one's own gain over the safety
and longevity of humanity, yes?
That's right.
Therefore, in acknowledgment of violating
said law, all Scouts are to be apprehended!
Old Man...
You think the fat cats will finally be satisfied?
I bet Reeves would be glad to know
he proved useful in the end.
There's still Levi to deal with...
I told you, he'll show up on his own.
We'll crush him when the time comes.
What do we do now?!
May I have a moment?
Hmm?
Get away from my husband, you lowlife!
In the battle of Trost District,
Mr. Reeves delayed the evacuation
by trying to take along his wealth.
So what?! Are you saying he deserved to die?!
However... given the current situation
with Trost on the verge of collapse...
He planted his feet in the city,
and using any means possible...
...he aided those with no place to go
while striving to revive the city.
Except, by somebody's hands
that dream was extinguished.
I promise you... I will avenge him.
My father... He was a teacher.
One day, we were learning history.
To protect themselves from the Titans,
humanity took refuge within the walls
and realized 100 years of peace.
In doing so, any records of our
earlier past were lost for all of time.
That's what we're all taught.
However, I... having doubts of my own,
asked my father a question.
My father evaded answering the question
and ended class as normal.
But...
After we got home,
my father answered my question.
He said the history books
given by the government
were full of contradictions and mysteries.
My father continued to tell me more,
and even as a child, I was astounded.
There's a reason he didn't tell that story to the
entire class, but I wasn't smart enough to know.
I'd been telling the other
kids my father's story,
and one day, the Military Police
came to question me.
My father didn't come home that day...
He died in some accident in a faraway town.
Based on what I knew,
my father was killed by the government.
One hundred and seven years ago...
Humanity that fled into these walls...
The King had altered their memories
to make them easy to rule.
That was my father's theory.
Oh? Because if they hadn't done that,
civilization within the walls could never succeed?
Yes.
Ever since I was a child, I've been thinking...
Why did my father have to die for
nothing more than getting close to the truth?
Even those in the government would
believe what they're doing is just.
However, I realized one thing about them...
What they're trying to protect is not humanity,
but their gardens, houses, and lands.
Rather, if anyone dares threaten their authority,
they'll be extinguished, whoever they are.
In the end, there was nothing
to justify my father's death.
My father was killed by human greed...
And by the foolishness of his own son.
Before I knew it, my father's theory
became truth inside my heart.
Now, my mission in life... It's to prove
my father's theory once and for all.
The Scout Regiment murdered a civilian!
Some of them have fled capture!
They're still on the loose!
If you spot any of these persons,
report it immediately!
Told you, didn't I?
They're the ones who had that Titan battle here
and destroyed practically everything!
I bet they're planning to use that
Eren monster to wipe us out!
Captain, we bought the supplies.
The Military Police were handing out these.
If this is true, the Scouts will be disbanded.
I heard they'll be hunting for us tonight.
They're also putting guards on all the vital roads,
and it's impossible to get through without a pass.
Captain, what now?
If we don't hurry, Eren...
Calm down.
They're using a wagon.
It'll take at least a day
to reach Reiss' territory.
We'll have to use that time
to come up with a plan.
Captain, I hear footsteps.
They're coming this way.
Those who throw away their life...
Those who believe in justice...
Those who protect the city...
Courage which swells up from memories
gives people the courage to fight.
Next episode: "Trust."